# **CHRIS OLSEN**

chris@chrisolsen.org +1 780-887-2008

#### WHY HIRE ME?

I have more than **15** years of experience in creating applications from concept to completion...the only way you can do it for this long is if you love what you do. I love it because learning new things is a requirement, and allows one to improve themselves everyday.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

## Sr. Software Developer 09/2020 to current

#### **Government of Alberta** Edmonton

Typescript React Svelte Angular Jest Storybook

- · Responsible for initiating the creation of the UI team
- Primary developer for the <u>UI Component</u> library for dev teams within the provincial government.
- Designed and developed core services made available to other teams.

### Sr. Software Developer 12/2018 to 07/2020

### CenturyLink Edmonton

Java Spring Boot AngularJS Python Cypress Docker MongoDB

- Helped to add disaster recovery functionality allowing for system recovery to CenturyLink, AWS or Azure cloud instances.
- Worked on Cloud Application Manager analytics backend and rewrote the testing component to allow for faster and selective testing.

## Software Developer (1 year contract) 07/2017 to 08/2018

### Alberta College of Pharmacists Edmonton

Elm Node.js AngularJS ServiceNow MSSQL

- Identified and fixed application usability and security deficiencies.
- Created UI designs for next version of the application.
- Developed Elm application to export ServiceNow data to Quickbooks .iif format.
- Implemented data migration CLI that optimized existing migration times to ServiceNow from over 5 hours to a few minutes.
- Created Elm application to convert old quickbook data type to csv files

### Software Developer (1 month contract) 07/2017 to 08/2017

#### **Ledcor** Edmonton

AngularJS Gulp

- Created a deployment system that decreased deployment time from 10 minutes to a few seconds.
- Reduced total application size by ~90%.

### Sr. Software Developer 04/2014 to 05/2016

#### **Showbie** Edmonton

Ember JS Go

- Developed web application replicating the existing iOS application for the web.
- Created web application which allowed school districts to manage teacher licenses.
- Built Go utility to convert .po files supplied by the translating service to the custom locale format required for Android, web and iOS.

### Software Developer | Architect 2011 to 2012

#### Mitremedia Edmonton

Ruby on Rails Nginx MySql PHP

- Optimized web applications created by bought-out companies (reduced response times from > 2min to less than 5 seconds).
- Server and deployment setup for existing applications.

### Android Developer | Architect 2010 to 2011

### **Drivewyze** Edmonton

Java Android Sglite3

- · Promoted to Architect after less than a year.
- Designed and developed Android application allowing semi drivers to receive bypass notifications from weigh stations.
- Responsible for creating and documenting logic for mobile devices and backend API.
- UI design for all mobile platforms

### Full-stack Developer 2010

### **Minigroup** Calgary

Ruby on Rails jQuery MySql

- Worked on the backend server logic and frontend jQuery
- Created search module to allow users to find notes, links and/or assets

### Web Developer (contract) 2008 to 2010

#### **Zedi** Edmonton

jQuery ASP.NET Oracle

- Successfully completed a scalability project which gave the site the ability to handle increased user load.
- Completed the SCADA drag n' drop interface that provided users that ability to monitor various on-site sensors.

### System Analyst II 2005-2007

#### **Alberta Education** Edmonton

ASP.NET VB.NET MSSQL

• Created web application that allowed special requests to be made and processed online.

### Software Developer (4 month internship) 2005

#### **Alberta Education** Edmonton

VB.NET Win32 MSSQL

- Developed in-house application that allowed flagged exams with scan errors and allowed them to be corrected online instead of manually.
- Increased the speed of the process scan errors more than 100 times.

#### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

#### Woddy

Workout of the day app tracker. Elm, Go, AppEngine

#### **MathOps**

Allows kids to practice their basic math skills and track their progress over time. Android

### LeagueSmart

Created game schedules and provided score/stat entry. RubyOnRails, MySql

### **Onlinelisting**

Allowed real-estate agents to create personal sites. RubyOnRails, MySql

### **EDUCATION**

- Udacity Intro to Self Driving Cars
- Udacity Android Developer Nanodegree
- Northern Alberta Institute of Technology
- University of Alberta: BSc Chemistry with Specialization

### **SKILLS**

Svelte React Typescript Elm Elixir Phoenix Go MySql PostgreSql